{
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": 1,
            "question": "Which of these products is sold by the brands Colgate, Oral-B and Sensodyne?",
            "answers": [
                "Deodorant",
                "Shampoo",
                "Toothpaste",
                "Sun cream"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Toothpaste"
        },
        {
            "id": 2,
            "question": "Which tool was used as a weapon by the Norse god Thor?",
            "answers": [
                "Pliers",
                "Hammer",
                "Screwdriver",
                "Saw"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Hammer"
        },
        {
            "id": 3,
            "question": "What is the name of the classic dessert consisting of sponge cake and ice cream covered in meringue?",
            "answers": [
                "Baked Rhode Island",
                "Baked Wyoming",
                "Baked Connecticut",
                "Baked Alaska"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Baked Alaska"
        },
        {
            "id": 4,
            "question": "Trigonometry is a branch of which subject?",
            "answers": [
                "Biology",
                "Economics",
                "Psychology",
                "Mathematics"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Mathematics"
        },
        {
            "id": 5,
            "question": "The hammer and sickle is one of the most recognisable symbols of which political ideology?",
            "answers": [
                "Communism",
                "Fascism",
                "Capitalism",
                "Socialism"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Communism"
        },
        {
            "id": 6,
            "question": "Which of these means a speech in a play where a character talks to themselves rather than to other characters?",
            "answers": [
                "Interlude",
                "Revue",
                "Soliloquy",
                "Chorus"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Soliloquy"
        },
        {
            "id": 7,
            "question": "Which of these is a religious event celebrated in Hinduism?",
            "answers": [
                "Diwali",
                "Ramadan",
                "Hanukkah",
                "Whitsun"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Diwali"
        },
        {
            "id": 8,
            "question": "Suffolk Punch and Hackney are types of what?",
            "answers": [
                "Carriage",
                "Wrestling style",
                "Horse",
                "Cocktail"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Horse"
        },
        {
            "id": 9,
            "question": "Which iconic horror film involves a couple whose newborn child is replaced at birth with the Antichrist?",
            "answers": [
                "The Shining",
                "Don't Look Now",
                "The Exorcist",
                "The Omen"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "The Omen"
        },
        {
            "id": 10,
            "question": "In the opera by Rossini, what is the first name of The Barber of Seville?",
            "answers": [
                "Tamino",
                "Alfredo",
                "Don Carlos",
                "Figaro"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Figaro"
        },
        {
            "id": 11,
            "question": "Which of these books is believed to have been inspired by the real-life experiences of the Scottish sailor Alexander Selkirk?",
            "answers": [
                "Moby Dick",
                "Robinson Crusoe",
                "Treasure Island",
                "The Count of Monte Cristo"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Robinson Crusoe"
        },
        {
            "id": 12,
            "question": "Which toxic substance is obtained from the pressed seeds of the castor oil plant?",
            "answers": [
                "Sarin",
                "Strychnine",
                "Ricin",
                "Cyanide"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Ricin"
        },
        {
            "id": 13,
            "question": "The word 'aristocracy' literally means power in the hands of whom?",
            "answers": [
                "The few",
                "The best",
                "The barons",
                "The rich"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "The best"
        },
        {
            "id": 14,
            "question": "From which author's work did scientists take the word 'quark'?",
            "answers": [
                "Lewis Carroll",
                "Edward Lear",
                "James Joyce",
                "Aldous Huxley"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Lewis Carroll"
        },
        {
            "id": 15,
            "question": "Which insect shorted out an early supercomputer and inspired the term 'computer bug'?",
            "answers": [
                "Moth",
                "Roach",
                "Fly",
                "Japanese beetle"
            ],
            "correct_answer": "Moth"
        }
    ]
}